

# **Fetullah Atas**

Robotic Software Engineer

#### **Contact Information**

Address

Taipei City, Taiwan

**Phone** 

+886-909-561-094

**Email Address** 

fetulahatas1@gmail.com

Website

jediofgever.github.io

#### **Skills**

C++

ROS1, ROS2

Mobile Robots, Robotic Arms

ROS Moveit!, ROS Navigation Stack

3D Vision and Perception

Motion Planning and Navigation

OpenCV, PCL, OpenVino

Linux, Git, QT

Object Recognition in 2D and 3D

### Languages

**English** 

**Kurdish** 

**Turkish** 

I am a highly motivated and passionate Software Engineer with a special interest for autonomous robots and its applications. Experienced on developing software for various robotics platforms(mobile, arms) ranging from research to industrial level. Strong understanding and software developmental skills in robot perception, scene understanding and planning. Fluent in C++ and ROS1, sufficient in Python. Currently focused on getting a stronger grasp of ROS2.

## **Work Experience**

## **Chicony Electronics Co.**

(08/2019 - Ongoing)

Robotic Software Engineer

Responsible for development of robotic project, with the aim of achieving vision

- Responsible for development of robotic project, with the aim of achieving vision based auto pick-place of various objects
- Developed QT based UI for interacting with robot
- Trained and validated various CNN architectures(MaskRCNN, YOLO) for custom object detection in 2D and 3D
- Contributed to a few open source ROS packages in order to include new models of industrial robots
- Rewrote a custom calibration stack(ROS stacks) for different types of camera calibration tasks(Hand-Eye, Eye-Base, Camera intrinsic calib), with an automated fashion
- Integrated various robot models(Staubli, Fanuc) with Gazebo simulator, for testing and validating software in advance
- Authored close to 10 ROS packages in context of the project
- Single-handedly achieved vision based pick and place that can be ported to any ROS supported 6DOF robots
- Started the RD process of building and simulating ROS2 based AGV
- Built a primitive version of differential drive Mobile robot that autonomously navigates in pre-built map(by google cartographer), uses the new Navigation2 by ROS2

## **Mindtronic Al**

(05/2018 - 03/2019)

Perception Engineer

- Responsible for autonomous vehicle and its sensor simulation under different simulators such as Gazebo and CARLA
- Took a part to design and apply the perception architecture of autonomous vehicle
- Integrated results of perception into vector map ,which was an unified representation of real world inside the system
- Wrote much simpler and efficient Cost-map which was used for local path planning, obstacle avoidance and other Grid Cell based perception algorithms
- Achieved obstacle detection and obstacle localization in unknown environments using Lidar data
- Developed C++ code for Lidar based Object detection and tracking for autonomous driving with Kalman filter
- Actively used PCL and OpenCV for segmentation, clustering and other manipulations on Lidar Point Clouds and Images
- Implemented several Gazebo models and world plugins including intelligent agents radar sensor plugin

## **National Taipei University of Technology**

(09/2017 - 08/2019)

Graduate Researche

- CNNs for object detection, mainly focused on urban areas for autonomous driving
- 2D and 3D SLAM of indoor environments using Google Cartographer for mobile robot navigation with ROS navigation stack
- Robot path planing and observing using IMU and 2D Lidar
- Sensor fusion for autonomous vehicle perception, especially Lidar and camera
- Sensor calibration tasks, Lidar and 3D camera(ZED) calibration
- 3D scene understanding using 3D Lidar point clouds and RGB image

#### **Education**

### **National Taipei University of Technology**

Master's Degree, Mechatronics Engineering

Thesis Topic: A New Real-Time 3D Detection Framework Based on Instance Segmentation

## **Istanbul Technical University**

(2016 - 2017)

(2017 - 2019)

Master's Degree, Mechatronics Engineering

Partially completed this degree

## **Istanbul Gelisim University**

(2011 - 2015)

Bachelor's Degree, Mechatronics Engineering

#### **Notable SIDE PROJECTS**

## **PointNet Custom Object Detection**

A project that show cases, train and testing of PointNet with custom objects/datasets

- Describes steps to prepare and label the data for training
- Provides scripts for data augmentation that helps improving overall accuracy
- Describes and provides pseudo C++ for collecting custom data from various depth cameras and Lidar. PointCloud2 type is supported.
- https://github.com/jediofgever/PointNet\_Custom\_Object\_Detection

### **ROS KITTI Perception**

Ros Package to access manipulate and process Raw KITTI dataset

- Perception extracted from self driving car sensors including Lidar, Radar, camera etc.
- Sensor fusion between Lidar and Camera
- Various utility functions that are used in autonomous vehicle development project
- Local cost map extracted from Lidar, to be used for collision avoidance
- https://github.com/jediofgever/ROS\_Raw\_Kitti\_Player

### References

#### Eduardo Munera, PhD

Senior Software Engineer eduardo.munera@gmail.com

#### Roy Le, PhD

Senior Software Engineer lemanhtrung@gmail.com

### Personal Information

#### **Date of Birth**

18th September 1993

#### Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fetatas/

#### Github

https://github.com/jediofgever